<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>danielorihuela</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on danielorihuela</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danielorihuela.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep004 challenge 03</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep004ch03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep004ch03/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep004 challenge 03. Category Misc.
Learning Journey In that challenge, we only have the hint. So, I went ahead to the webpage used in this episode. Next to the &amp;ldquo;FAQs&amp;rdquo; tab, I found the &amp;ldquo;Contributing&amp;rdquo; tab.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep004 challenge 01</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep004ch01/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep004ch01/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep004 challenge 01. Category Web Exploitation.
Learning Journey When we open the challenge, it redirects us to a copy of Google Bug Hunter webpage of the original Google Bug Hunter webpage.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep004 challenge 02</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep004ch02/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep004ch02/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep004 challenge 02. Category Web Exploitation.
Learning Journey In this challenge, we are given some code. We have to find the vulnerability and login as &amp;ldquo;tin&amp;rdquo;. Let&amp;rsquo;s check the code.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep003 challenge 02</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep003ch02/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep003ch02/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep003 challenge 02. Category Escape Restricted Shell.
Learning Journey The description gives us the command to connect to a remote machine.
At this point, we can try winning the game or cheating, as the hint suggests.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep003 challenge 03</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep003ch03/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep003ch03/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep003 challenge 03. Category Android.
Learning Journey Opening the challenge gives us a zip containing two files: an apk and a QR code. First things first, let&amp;rsquo;s install the application and see if we can scan the QR code and what&amp;rsquo;s the result.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep003 challenge 01</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep003ch01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep003ch01/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep003 challenge 01. Category Misc.
Learning Journey The description tell us how to connect to the machine with socat. However, it requires a password. I tried to guess it with no luck.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep002 challenge 03</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep002ch03/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep002ch03/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep002 challenge 03. This challenge is about Escaping Restricted Shell.
Learning Journey The description tells us how to connect to a remote shell.
Once connected, we get access to a shell.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep002 challenge 02</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep002ch02/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep002ch02/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep002 challenge 02. This challenge is about Forensics.
Learning Journey The challenge gives us a zip containing a readme file and the logs in a csv file. The readme explains how to install timesketch using docker.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep002 challenge 01</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep002ch01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep002ch01/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep002 challenge 01. This challenge is about Steganography.
Learning Journey The challenge gives us the following image.
It&amp;rsquo;s an RGBA file.
The first thing that came to mind with my basic knowledge of image steganography was the LSB (i.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep001 challenge 03</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep001ch03/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep001ch03/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep001 challenge 03. This challenge is about Reverse Engineering.
Learning Journey After opening the challenge, we see a chess website similar to the one in the ep000 ch01.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep001 challenge 02</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep001ch02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep001ch02/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep001 challenge 02. This challenge is about Reverse Engineering.
Learning Journey After opening the challenge, we get a zip file containing an executable with the name wannacry.
As a first step, I extracted the strings from the executable with strings wannacry.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep000 challenge 01</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep000ch01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep000ch01/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post I explain how I solved ep000 challenge 01. This challenge is about Web Exploitation.
Learning Journey After opening the challenge, we see the following screen.
Winning the game at this point is not the intended way to solve the challenge.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep000 challenge 02</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep000ch02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep000ch02/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep000 challenge 02. This challenge is about Web Exploitation.
Learning Journey After opening the challenge, we see the log search tool.
The Log Search Tool is simple. It has two options.</description></item><item><title>H4ck1ng G00gl3 ep001 challenge 01</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep001ch01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/h4ck1ng-g00gl3-ep001ch01/</guid><description>Table of Contents Introduction Learning Journey Introduction H4ck1ng G00gl3 is a series of security challenges published on October 2022 where the only way to win is to think like a hacker. In this post, I explain how I solved ep001 challenge 01. This challenge is about Reverse Engineering.
Learning Journey After opening the challenge, we get a zip file. This zip file contains another compressed file that includes two files.</description></item><item><title>Deploy blog written with org-mode on GitHub Pages</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/deploy-blog-written-with-org-mode-on-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/deploy-blog-written-with-org-mode-on-github-pages/</guid><description>Table of Contents Context Goal (expected final workflow) Steps Create GitHub repository Upload Hugo configuration Create GitHub Action workflow Conclusion Context I have been using emacs to write in org-mode for some time now. I love it. So, I decided to start writing a personal blog with it. However, I did not have the tool to create the blog and the means to publish it. I selected a static site generator (SSG) called Hugo for my first problem.</description></item><item><title>Test github action build hugo webpage</title><link>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/test_action_post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielorihuela.github.io/posts/test_action_post/</guid><description>Test github action build hugo webpage</description></item></channel></rss>